是, 大臣  第2季第6集
THE LAST FANTASY | TLF HALFCD TeaM
压制：beiming6@TLF  字幕：破烂熊
仅供交流  严禁商用
-=破烂熊字幕组=-
翻译:claudia 校对&时间轴:tpring
生活质量
The Quality of Life
他还在跟宣传秘书开会 汉弗莱爵士
He's still with the Press Officer, Sir Humphrey.
您先喝杯咖啡?
Would you like a coffee?
伯纳 如果大臣和宣传秘书在一起
If the Minister is with the Press Officer,
我们吃顿大餐也有时间
we've probably got time for a six-course lunch.
早 戴斯蒙爵士      早 汉弗莱      哦 戴斯蒙
Morning, Humphrey. Desmond!
他在开会 用不了多久的
He's got somebody with him, but he'll only be a moment.
你试过他口风了?     试了 恐怕目前希望不大
Did you sound him out about...? Yes, but it doesn't look hopeful.
为什么 我们银行只不过想
All my bank wants is to put six
在新办公楼上加盖6层而已 没问题嘛
little storeys on the new office block.
你读今早的金融时报了吗?     我从来不读
Read the Financial Times today? Never do!
你是银行家嘛 当然要读金融时报
You're a banker, surely you read the Financial Times?
看也看不懂 全是经济理论
Can't understand it. Full of economic theory.
那你买它干吗?     唉 专业形象的一部分嘛
Why do you buy it? It's part of the uniform.
我花了30年才搞懂凯恩斯理论
Took me 30 years to understand Keynes' economics.
刚摸着门 大家又去追捧新货币理论了
I'd just cottoned when everyone got hooked on monetarist ideas
你知道 米尔顿·舒曼说的"我要自由市场"
you know, "I Want To Be Free", by Milton Shulman.
米尔顿·弗里德曼?     干嘛都叫米尔顿?
Milton Friedman? Why are they all called Milton?
我就知道米尔顿·凯恩斯
I've only got as far as Milton Keynes.
梅纳德·凯恩斯?
Maynard Keynes?
肯定有个米尔顿·凯恩斯
I'm sure there's a Milton Keynes.
对对 是有一个
Yes, there is, it's...
请坐
Sit down.
你还没看过大臣昨晚
You didn't read about the Minister's speech
致建筑业协会的讲话吧?
to the Architectural Association last night,
抨击了摩天大楼群 媒体反响很好
attacking skyscraper office blocks?
我们那幢可不是摩天大楼
Ours isn't a skyscraper.
有几层来着?     38层
How many storeys? 38.
再加这6层 就是44层
44 with the extra six we're asking for.
可他说最高不许超过8层
He was talking about the maximum tolerable height being eight.
得了小汉 你肯定能劝服他吧?
Surely you can talk him out of it?
一点点往上加 8 12 18...
Work him upwards? 8, 12, 18...
你不就干这个嘛 劝他放弃政策
That's your job talking him out of things.
对 可别忘了他承诺过
Don't forget, there's a promise
限制高层建筑
to prevent any more high-rise buildings
写在他竞选宣言的环境部分
in the environment section of the manifesto.
那就没戏啦?    也不一定
Does that scupper it? Not necessarily.
你看 每位大臣的高级公务员
There's an implicit pact offered to every Minister
都会向其暗示一笔交易
by his senior officials.
如果大臣帮我们实施的政策
If the Minister implements the opposite
与他的承诺截然相反
policy to the one he's pledged to,
一旦上任 他必然发现宣言不可行
which, once in office, he will see is incorrect,
我们就帮他掩饰 假装他遵守了承诺
we'll help him to pretend he's following his manifesto.
这交易挺合理的     听上去确实合理
That's a very reasonable offer. It sounds reasonable.
不幸的是 戴斯蒙 政客们尽管有很多
Unfortunately, among the many
卓越的特质
extraordinary qualities politicians possess,
讲理却不怎么被他们看重
reasonableness isn't the first that springs to mind.
至少一般大臣都是如此
Not when one contemplates the average Minister.
而我们的大臣非常一般
And our Minister is very average.
但是我们确实需要加盖几层
But we need those extra floors.
而且如果你退休后加入董事会
And if you're joining the board when you retire,
没有办公室就麻烦了
it'll be tricky if there's no office to put you in.
在停车场上搭个活动会客室?
Entertaining your visitors in a Portakabin in the car park?
我又没说不批给你
I'm not saying you won't get permission
只是今天不行 耐心点
just not today. Be patient.
只要大臣拍个板不就完了吗?
Surely if a Minister's made a decision, that's it?
你怎能这么想?     他决定的就是决议呗
What gave you that idea? Surely a decision's a decision?
我们满意的才是决议
Only if it's the decision you want.
要不然 只是一时挫折而已
If not, it's just a temporary setback.
大臣都像小孩子 容易冲动
Ministers are like small children:
今天吵着要什么东西
They want something desperately
明天就忘得一干二净
and next day forget they asked for it.
大臣不是效忠皇冠吗?    你当这雅号怎么来的?
He is a Minister of the Crown. You know why he's called that?
他说话一般不过大脑
He's always talking off the top of his head...
或者说完就抛到脑后
or through the back of it!
你要反对他的决定?     不不不
You won't accept his decision? No, no, no.
我要从热烈欢迎 坚决支持开始
I start by accepting it and supporting it enthusiastically,
然后请他交给我完成
then I tell him to leave it to me.
汉弗莱 搞建筑的来了
Humphrey, the architect fellow.
早上好 克劳福 请坐 大臣还得一会儿
Morning, Crawford. The Minister won't keep a moment.
那得怎么办?
So, what's going to happen?
我先跟他谈谈
I'll have a minute with him first,
但今天上午别指望太多
but don't expect too much this morning.
就当成小孩子为米饭布丁闹腾吧
Think of it as a child's tantrum over a rice pudding.
今天碰也不碰 明天就要两份
Won't touch it today and yet wants two helpings tomorrow.
啊 米饭布丁 好啊
Ah, rice pudding... good.
其实我也满喜欢米饭布丁的
I always liked rice pudding.
大臣 这真是太棒了
Minister, it's really excellent.
"哈克大声疾呼 反对高层建筑"      是不错
"Hacker speaks out against tower blocks."
"大臣咬定摩天大楼不松口"
"Minister's courageous stand on high buildings."
难道我是蜘蛛人么
I sound like a steeplejack.
这是高端的 大众媒体呢?
What about the popular press?
坊间那些日报是怎么说我的?
How do I get into the mass circulation dailies?
有照片吗?     报纸一般爱登漂亮姑娘的照片
What about a photograph? The papers like photos of a pretty girl
这个标准 我算够不上了
I don't quite qualify on that score.
不 我是说 您可以去选美比赛当评委
Judge a beauty contest
亲吻冠军 这就上报了
a photo of you kissing the winner.
太俗了吧 再说要是登我的照片
If my picture's in the papers,
人们应该关注我 而不是美女
people should look at me, not some pretty girl.
不然跟小动物或小孩拍照也行
Otherwise, something with cuddly animals or small children,
比如今天下午访问城市农场
like this afternoon's visit to the city farm.
对对 都刊登了吗? 邮报 镜报 每日快报
Is everything laid on Mail, Mirror, Express?
还有太阳报 今日头条 晚间新闻     晚间新闻?
And the Sun, Today and Nationwide. Nationwide?
我会上电视吗?     走运的话
Will I be on telly? With any luck.
好 这还差不多     先生 您是效忠皇冠的嘛
Well done! You are a Minister of the Crown, sir.
您还得和一群小驴子合个影
There's some baby donkeys laid on to be photographed with.
驴子?     是的 先生
Donkeys? Yes, sir.
太阳报特别询问
The Sun specifically asked
您能否站在驴子中间拍照
if you could be photographed amongst the donkeys.
驴子啊 你说呢 伯纳?
What do you think, Bernard?
即使太阳报动机纯良
Even if the Sun has no ulterior motive
侦探报也会大做文章
it'll be a gift for Private Eye.
"您和其他驴子"
You with a crowd of other donkeys.
是他们会这么说 大臣 或者"核心内阁会议"
That's what they would say. Or a meeting of the Inner Cabinet.
你来干嘛 伯纳?
What are you here for, Bernard?
对 汉弗莱爵士来了     好吧
Sir Humphrey's here. Very well.
农场肯定还有小猪吧
There's also some little pigs.
我看小猪也强不到哪去
I don't think that's a great improvement. 95()
想想"猪嘴刨食"(以权谋私)的笑话 用用脑子
Snouts in the trough jokes pull yourself together!
可是大臣      我最多和羊羔拍个照 最多了
I will consent to be photographed with a lamb, that's all.
啊 汉弗莱     早上好
Ah, Humphrey. Good morning.
大臣 戴斯蒙·格雷布克爵士来了
Sir Desmond Glazebrook is outside.
格雷布克? 那个老嚷嚷反政府的笨蛋?
Glazebrook? That old fool who makes anti-Government speeches?
就是他 您任命他为
Yes, and you appointed him
工业合作主席
chairman of the co-partnership commission.
是哦 他有何贵干?
What's he want?
他找您谈一个申请
He wants to talk about his forthcoming application
给他在建的银行大厦多批几层楼
to put more storeys on his bank's office block.
当前要打击的正是这个 汉弗莱
That's just the thing we must stop, Humphrey.
得有人为环境登高一呼
Somebody has to speak out about the environment,
在摩天大楼上勇敢站出来
take a stand on high buildings.
这造型拍下来登报挺好
That would make a good press photograph.
谢谢 伯纳
Thank you, Bernard.
听您的 大臣 不过他的项目不错
It's up to you, but he does have a good case.
您读了背景资料吗?
Have you read the background papers?
当然读了 提醒我一下
Yes, of course. Remind me.
银行指出
The bank points out that
附近已经有几幢摩天大楼
there are already several tower blocks nearby,
这次是为了银行国际部
and it is the international division of the bank
迅速扩张
expanding rapidly.
银行得建在市中心
It needs a central location.
会大幅增加城市税收
It would bring in revenue for the city.
可不是 钱钱钱 美观呢 汉弗莱?
Typical! Money, money, money. What about beauty, Humphrey?
确实啊 大臣 美观
Indeed, Minister, beauty.
拿笔记下来 伯纳
Make a note of that, Bernard.
我们的孩子呢 子孙后代呢?
What about our children? And their children?
确实 大臣 "子孙后代" 伯纳
Exactly, Minister, "Children's children", Bernard.
汉弗莱 你到底侍奉上帝还是财神?
Who are you serving? God or Mammon?
我侍奉您 大臣
I'm serving you, Minister.
既然如此 汉弗莱 请戴斯蒙爵士进来
In that case, Humphrey, show Sir Desmond in.
格雷布克 我让你盖...
Glazebrook! I'll give him high-rise buildings...
戴斯蒙爵士 幸会幸会 有什么可以效劳吗?
Sir Desmond, how nice to see you! What can I do for you?
就盖几层楼的事儿 加盖6层
It's these extra storeys, six of them.
正式申请随后递交
We'll make a formal application later
在此之前 您有什么指点吗?
but any guidance you can give us...?
话说在前头 我一向反对高层建筑
I warn you that I have misgivings about tower blocks.
不然怎么赚钱啊 多造6层才能大翻身
This is how we make profits. Six extra storeys and we clean up.
不然这个项目只有可怜的28%的赚头
Without them, we'll only make a measly 28% on the project.
懂了 净讲利润是不是     不是净利润 是毛利
It's just profits, is it? Not "Just profits", it's profits!
除了钱你就不想点别的?     不想 怎么?
Don't you think of anything but money? No, why?
美观怎么说呢?     美观?这是幢楼 不是幅画
What about beauty? It's a building, not an oil painting.
环境问题呢?
And the environment?
对 我保证让大楼融入环境
We'll make sure it's part of the environment.
都杵在那了 想不融入也难
It's bound to be, once it's there.
抱歉 戴斯蒙爵士     还有一件事 大臣
I'm sorry, Sir Desmond... There's one thing, Minister.
报上说 政府发过这种批文
As you know, similar permission was given
给纽约大通银行
to Chartered of New York,
要是拒绝英国银行...
so to refuse a British bank...
就是 没问题了吧?
Exactly! So it's all right?
呃..不 不行
Er... well... no. No, it isn't.
他妈的 怎么不行?    并...并不一定...
Why not, damn it? It-it-it's not necessarily...
大臣是担心一幢新楼
The Minister is concerned that another tall building
会破坏已有的天际线
will clutter the skyline.
对 破坏天际线
That's right, it would clutter the skyline.
也很担心 项目所需的大批工人
He's also worried that more workers in the area
会拖累城市交通系统
would strain the transport system.
我很担心交通系统
I'm worried about public transport.
而且 他还指出高楼会挡住
Furthermore, he points out that it will overshadow
附近小学操场的阳光      没错
the playground of the St Joseph's Primary School.
大楼上可以俯瞰私家花园
It would overlook private gardens
从而侵犯了个人隐私
which would be an intrusion of privacy.
隐私 污染
Privacy! Pollution!
另外他还指出 一针见血啊大臣
Furthermore, the Minister points out, most astutely
贵行在不远处还有块空地
that the bank owns a vacant site close by
正好能解决你们扩张的需求
which would accommodate your expansion needs.
哪里?     那里
Where? There.
那不是河吗?
That's the river, isn't it?
大臣指的是这块地
The Minister was referring to this site.
是我们的吗?     是的 戴斯蒙爵士
Is that ours? It is, Sir Desmond.
干什么用的?     计划用于三期工程
What's it for? It's scheduled for phase three.
那是三期工程用的 再说它在400码以外呢
That's scheduled for phase three. it's 400 yards away.
董事们没法跑到400码之外去吃午饭
Difficult for the board to walk 400 yards to lunch...
吃完就更走不回来了
...and impossible to walk back afterwards.
戴斯蒙爵士 正式申请你们爱交就交
Put in your formal application by all means,
不过我决心已定
but that will be my decision.
大臣 要是我们设计一种新的米饭布丁呢?
Minister, suppose we designed a different rice pudding?
什么?     什么?
What? What?
米饭布丁?
Rice pudding?
对 银行家管高楼叫米饭布丁 大臣
Bankers' jargon for high-rise buildings.
是吗?
Is it?
伯纳 请送送戴斯蒙爵士
Bernard, show Sir Desmond out.
再会 戴斯蒙爵士
Bye, Sir Desmond.
哦 好的
Oh, yes. Right.
多谢你 汉弗莱 你那些提醒太及时了
Thank you, your reminders were very helpful.
我很荣幸 大臣     我们真是绝配啊
A pleasure. Real teamwork, what?
而且格雷布克还是你熟人
Especially as Glazebrook is your chum.
对 我们是老朋友了 大臣
We're very old friends.
不过至交好友又怎能比得上
But it is as naught compared to
公务员对大臣的忠诚?
a civil servant's duty to his Minister.
汉弗莱 你说真的吗?     当然是真的 大臣
Humphrey, do you mean that? Of course, Minister!
你太好了     谢谢夸奖
How very nice. Thank you.
半点了 大臣     我得赶快了
It's after half past. I've got to dash.
紧急任务?   非常紧急
Urgent appointment? Very urgent.
内阁委员会?     对...不是 差不多的
Cabinet committee? That sort of thing.
您能签了这个吗 大臣? 非常重要
Could you sign this? It's extremely urgent.
非签不可吗? 我已经晚了
Do I have to? I'm late already.
对 可这是行政命令      干什么的?
It's an administrative order to formalise Government powers
该命令正式授权政府
for the utilisation of unused local authority land
利用地方上的未规划土地
until development commences,
当然 规划后再交还地方
then it reverts to the authority.
非得现在签吗? 怎么没提交下院?      十万火急
Do I have to sign now? Why hasn't it been before the House?
当然 如果是法规
If it were a statutory instrument
就要下院审核
it would have to go before the House,
可这是行政命令
but it's an administrative order,
根据环境法案第7条第3款
under section seven of the Environment Act,
就是管辖权条款
which is an enabling section,
规定大臣有权出台政策
empowering the Minister to make regulations
对地方上未开垦土地
regarding unused local authority land
随时进行适当调整
as necessary from time to time
只要在该法案框架内 您当然记得的
within the framework of the Act, as I'm sure you recollect.
为什么没提交下院?
Why doesn't it go before the House?
我说了 如果是法规
If it were a statutory instrument
就要下院审核
it would have to go before the House,
但这是行政命令
but because it is an administrative order
根据环境法案第7条第3款...
under section seven of the...
好好汉弗莱 我签完了 快点伯纳     谢谢 大臣
All right, Humphrey, I have signed it!
这个为什么这么急?
Why was that so urgent?
其实并不急     您刚才说很急
It wasn't. But you said it was.
不是很急 但是非常重要
It wasn't urgent, but it was important.
任何将大臣的决策权
Any document transferring decision-making power
转移给我们的文件都很重要
from Ministers to us is important.
为什么?     哦 伯纳
Why? Oh, Bernard...!
拜托你别呆头呆脑的行不行
Don't be obtuse, please.
这是从政治中解救政府之道
It helps take Government out of politics.
惟其如此 英国才能长存
It's Britain's only chance of survival.
就不能等他不急的时候吗?
Couldn't it have waited until he wasn't in a hurry?
伯纳 要让大臣不问缘由直接签字
When we want Ministers to sign without asking questions
就得挑他们慌慌张张的时候
we wait until they're in a hurry
注意力最薄弱
and their concentration is weakest.
容易得手 所以要让他们忙着
That's why we keep them on the go.
伯纳 大臣这么匆忙是要去什么神秘地点呀?
Bernard, where was the Minister rushing off to so secretively?
访问塔区的一个小学生农场
A school children's city farm in Tower Hamlets.
唉 这位仁兄为露脸真是无所不为啊
My God! The things that man will do for publicity.
他是去参观还是被参观呢?
Is he going as a visitor or as an exhibit?
很好笑 汉弗莱爵士    啊?
Very droll, Sir Humphrey. What?
菲利普太太? 我是大臣的宣传秘书普利查德
Mrs Philips? I'm Bill Pritchard, the Minister's Press Officer.
大臣 这位是菲利普太太 农场主管
This is Mrs Philips, the warden of the park.
干的漂亮 您好      您好
How do you do?
我是BBC的 没拍到您到达的场景
BBC TV. We didn't get your arrival
能重来一次吗?
could we have it again?
什么?     您能否重新到达一次?      当然可以
Sorry? Could you arrive again?
什么叫重新到达? 他已经到这里了啊
How can he arrive again? He's already here.
拍摄需要     行吗?
For the cameras. Do you mind?
什么行吗?
Mind what?
就拍个到达场景
Let's see you arriving.
这种事常有吗?      对对
Does this often happen?
我搞不懂...
But I don't understand...
准备 开拍
Turn over... Action!
大家快挥手
Wave, everybody!
欢迎您 大臣      非常高兴能来这里
Welcome, Minister. It's a great pleasure.
您能来太好了
I'm glad you've come.
我们请过别的名人 谁都不肯来
We tried other celebrities but nobody could come.
停机      怎么啦
Cut. What?
停机停机      停机
Cut, cut, cut! Cut.
这段能掐掉吧?     好 可是...
We'll cut that out, right? Yes, but...
别可是了 掐掉
Not but, cut!
请容许我向您介绍市长阁下
May I introduce you to His Worship, the Mayor?
电视执照税又涨了
Licence fees are coming up again.
好啦 给我讲讲这个
Now, tell me all about this.
这是一只小猪
This is a piglet.
不是 讲讲城市农场
No, tell me about this city farm.
哦 有50多座城市农场
There are over 50 city farms
都建在城中荒地
built in urban wasteland
好让难得下乡的城里孩子
to give children who seldom see the countryside
有机会观察牲畜和粮食生产
a chance to understand livestock and food production.
太周到了 今年是你们第一年吧?
What a wonderful idea! And this is your first anniversary?
是的     恭喜恭喜
Yes. Congratulations.
大臣 能否拍个您向
Could we have a shot congratulating
菲利普太太道喜的镜头?
Mrs Philips for the television?
当然可以 听你们的
Certainly, by all means.
别太把自个当盘菜...对不起 小猪
Everyone's a ham! Sorry.
今年是建成第一年吧? 不错
So this is your first anniversary here? Good.
恭喜恭喜 干得好
Congratulations. Well done.
非常成功 非常好
Jolly good show. Very good.
镜头够了吧?
Got enough now?
请您抓紧时间 大臣 先发表讲话
If we may hurry you, make your speech first,
然后会见农场员工
and then meet the staff.
我想和他们一起接受采访
I'd like to do the interview with some of those.
员工?     不 孩子们和动物
Staff? No, the children and animals.
有声吗...还行
Is this working?
演讲稿呢?     给您了 大臣
Got my speech? I gave it to you.
没有 在你那呢     是吗?
No, you've got it.
我们很荣幸请到了詹姆斯·哈克先生
It gives me pleasure to welcome Mr James Hacker,
行政事务部大臣
the Minister for Administrative Affairs,
他从百忙之中抽空
who has found time in his busy schedule
莅临我们农场的周年庆
to be with us today to celebrate our first anniversary.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢大家 很高兴今天和各位欢聚一堂
Thank you. It's a great pleasure to be here with you all today.
大家知道 这是变化的年代
You know, things are changing fast.
当今世界瞬息万变
We live in a world of change.
电脑芯片改变着我们的生活
The silicon chip is changing our lives.
生活质量日益重要
Quality of life is becoming more and more important.
环境保护 可持续发展
Environment, conservation
污染治理 孩子们的未来
problems of pollution, the future of our children,
子子孙孙的未来 都是今天的议题
and our children's children. These are today's issues.
就目前受到广泛关注的
There is, quite rightly, increasing concern
高层建筑问题
about high-rise buildings.
我乐意向大家保证
I'm happy to reassure you,
建筑协会会员们...
members of the Architectural Association...
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
这是昨天的稿子
It's yesterday's speech.
我只有这份 您掏掏口袋 大臣
It's the one I have, look in your pocket.
真抱歉
So sorry!
我昨天也讲了话所以...
I made a speech yesterday and...
今天来到城市农场 我十分荣幸
It's a great pleasure to be here at the city farm today.
大家知道 这是变化的年代
You know, things are changing fast.
当今世界瞬息万变
We live in a world of change.
电脑芯片改变着我们的生活
The silicon chip... is changing our lives.
生活质量日益重要
Quality of life is more important...
污染...子子孙孙的未来...
Pollution... future of our children's children...
都是今天的议题...建造城市农场
These are the issues... The city farm movement
这一有趣而重要的设施
is a welcome and important addition
造福了城市儿童
to the way of life for children in cities.
政府认为 它极大地促进了
We feel they play an vital part
儿童的教育和社会生活
in children's educational and social life.
我们应不遗余力使其蓬勃发展
We shall do all we can to help this movement flourish.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
苏·罗雷来了 现在能做访谈吗？
Sue Lawley's arrived, can we do the interview now?
好 找最可爱的孩子和动物来行吗?      没问题
Yes, set it up with the most attractive children and animals.
谢谢您的发言 大臣      很荣幸
Thank you for saying that, Minister.
可以指望您的支持吧?
Can we really rely on your support?
当然可以      您看
Of course you can.
我们的租约年底就到期了 得想办法续约才行
Our lease is running out and we have to get it extended.
我没法干涉这个 但我会尽力
I can't really influence it, but I'll try to
使农场蓬勃发展
help this movement to flourish.
大臣 现在访谈行吗? 这是晚间新闻的苏·罗雷
Would you do the interview now? This is Sue Lawley
苏·罗雷 久仰久仰
Sue Lawley, what a great pleasure.
我可是您的热心观众 大概是最热心的
I do believe I'm probably your greatest fan!
抱歉打搅 大臣
Sorry to butt in,
能给孩子和员工们签几个名吗?
but could the children and staff get autographs?
签名? 当然可以
Autographs? Certainly.
行了 签够了
Come on, that's enough.
好吧 要怎么访谈?
What did you want to say?
我先问主管几个问题
I'll ask some questions of the warden
再请您评论
and then come to you for comments.
没问题 我们要站哪?    我觉得这不错
Where would you like us to be? Here.
要孩子和小动物吗?     要 太好了
Perhaps with animals and children? Yes, splendid!
让这个可爱的小女孩坐您腿上 谢谢
Put this sweet little girl on your knee, Mr Hacker.
好 行了 快拍吧
All right, let's get on with it.
准备 开拍了 苏
Turn over! We're running, Sue.
主管女士 听说贵农场租约年底就到期了
Warden, I understand the lease of this city farm will run out
是的 我们很担心
Yes, we've been worried about this.
但我向哈克先生反映之后
But I've just had a word with Mr Hacker,
他表示会保证
and he has indicated that he will ensure
农场顺利运营
that this farm can carry on.
大臣 您会如何保障农场运营呢?
Minister, how will you ensure this farm keeps running?
嗯...你看...苏...
Er... well... you see... Sue...
事实是 这点我要强调
The fact is, and let me make this clear...
现今生活质量日益重要
Quality of life is becoming more important,
环境保护 可持续发展 污染治理
the environment, conservation, problems of pollution...
我们孩子的未来
The future of our children...
子子孙孙的未来 都是今天的议题
and our children's children. These are today's issues.
大臣 太谢谢您了      停      伯纳
Minister, thank you.
对了 昨天你那位上电视了
I saw your chap on the television last night
抱了个小兔子
cuddling a rabbit.
塔区的圣方济各(天主教的动物与环境圣徒)
St Francis of Tower Hamlets.
他去那儿干吗?
What was it in aid of?
拉啮齿动物的选票吧
After the rodent vote, I imagine.
这些城市农场倒不错啊
Quite a good idea, those city farms.
弗兰克 你们还在操心塔区的停车问题?
Are you still worried about parking at Tower House?
难着呢 塔区可是
Desperately! It's the major blockage to
国税监察员的大本营
recruiting Inland Revenue inspectors.
那里正有1.2亩地方机动土地
There's a 1.2 acre local authority site nearby
租约就要到期了
with the lease running out.
对 但我们无权征用啊     现在有了
But we haven't the authority. You have now.
你是指第7条那个行政命令?     于昨日签署
You mean an order under Section 7?! Signed yesterday.
汉弗莱 你太棒了 怎么办到的
Humphrey! How did you manage it?
现在场地是干嘛用的?     无关紧要
What's the site used for now? Nothing of any significance.
小学生的城市农场
A city farm for school children.
就像圣徒先生访问的那家?
Like the one St Francis was visiting?
不会就是那家吧
Not the one?
我就说这种东西不该办
I've always said those things are a bad idea.
不卫生 威胁公众健康
Unhygienic and a danger to public health.
你们最好赶快 趁他们续约之前
might be good to move quickly, before the lease were renewed.
当然 不过大臣不就难做人了吗?
Surely. Won't it put your Minister in a spot?
我自有办法救他     就知道你有 要咖啡吗?
I'm sure I'll find him a way out. I'm sure you will. Coffee?
不了 谢谢 得回去参见圣徒了
No, thanks, I must be getting back to Assisi.
谢谢你的招待 弗兰克    别客气
Thank you for lunch. Not at all.
一路顺风     天主保佑
Enjoy your trip. Bless you.
戴斯蒙?
Desmond?
是你啊 汉弗莱
It's you, Humphrey.
我有办法让大臣吃米饭布丁了
I think I know how to get the Minister to eat his rice pudding.
晚报来了 大臣
Evening paper, Minister.
中心页     是吗
Centre page. I say!
跨版图片 真不错啊
Double-page spread, what about that!
"塔区的圣方济各"
"The St Francis of Tower Hamlets."
一张我和小鸭子 还有一张我和小女孩
There's a picture of me with ducks. Another with a small girl.
一位黑...少数民族...混血...我是说...
A black... ethnic... multi... you know, one of...
公众效应真不错
What good publicity!
是 大臣      还有城市农场没有?
Are there any more city farms to visit?
曼彻斯特 伯明翰 格拉斯哥
Manchester, Birmingham, Glasgow.
边缘...不对 特别开发区有吗?
The marginal, I mean, the special development areas.
伯纳 你看这跨版报道      是是 大臣
Bernard, how about this double-page spread?
今早镜报和昨天晚间新闻的头条
Top of the Mirror, Nationwide last night.
怎么不说话 怎么啦?
You're very quiet, what's the matter?
菲利普太太来了 大臣      哪个菲利普?
Mrs Philips, the warden of the city farm you visited yesterday
昨天那家农场的主管
the warden of the city farm you visited yesterday
扬名了她很高兴吧?
Is she pleased with the publicity?
看样子不高兴     怎么?
She doesn't seem pleased. Why not?
农场要关门了     关门?
The farm's being closed. Closed?!
明年之前 改成国税监察员停车场
It's being turned into a car park for Inland Revenue inspectors.
天哪 媒体会怎么说?
My God, what will they say about this?
"孩子和小动物被税吏挤走"
"Children and animals evicted by taxman."
"大臣背弃电视宣言"
"Minister goes back on TV pledge."
老天 得赶紧阻止 想想办法 比尔
Heavens! This must be stopped. Do something!
哪个白痴批准的?     您自己 大臣
What idiot authorised that? You did.
什么?     您昨天签署的行政命令
What?
授权政府使用
The order you signed yesterday giving Government
地方机动土地
power over local authority land.
第7条第3款     叫汉弗莱来
Section 7, subsection 3. Get Humphrey.
他马上来 大臣 可菲利普太太到前厅了
He's on his way and Mrs Philips is in the private office.
最不想见的就是她
She's that last person I want to see.
这是本世纪最大灾难
This is the greatest disaster this century.
本世纪有两次世界大战
There were two world wars.
抢摊登陆是一回事
Fighting on the beaches is one thing
赶走动物和小孩
evicting animals and children
给收税的腾地可严重多了 啊 汉弗莱
for tax inspectors' cars is another. Ah, Humphrey!
大臣 我看到您昨晚上电视了 非常精彩
Minister, I saw you on television last night. What a treat!
别提电视了 谁关的城市农场?
Never mind that, what about the city farm being closed?
对了 财政部...     得阻止他们
The Treasury... It's got to be stopped!
可惜这是财政部决议
Unfortunately, it's a Treasury decision
我们无权干涉
and beyond our jurisdiction.
我要撤回那道命令     恐怕不可行 或很困难
I shall revoke the order. That is impossible. Or difficult.
不是上策 违反法律 总之肯定摊上了一项
Or inadvisable. Or requires legislation. One of those.
就算撤销 也不能
Anyway, it could not invalidate an action
追溯既往决定
taken while the order was in force.
我不管 就算女王教皇都在...
I don't care if it's the Queen and the Pope...
叛徒      什么 不至于吧
Judas! I say, look here.
你保证支持我们的     抱歉 我没...
You promised to support us! I'm sorry...
你必须让我们续约
You must see that our lease is renewed.
亲爱的女士 恐怕大臣无权...抱歉
My dear lady, it's not in the Minister's p...
哈克先生 你放过话的
Mr Hacker, you have given your word.
你要食言吗?
Are you going to keep it?
我会尽力...想办法...
I shall leave no stone... every avenue...
尽一切可能...
everything that is humanly possible...
就是不行喽?     不
You mean, no. No.
对 我不会 也就是会 绝对不会
Yes, I mean no. I mean yes. Definitely not. No.
对 我不会
Yes, I mean, no.
很好 别怪我没警告过你
Very well. Don't say I haven't warned you.
我丈夫是每日快报副主编
My husband is Deputy Features Editor of the Express.
明天一早 你就会臭名远播
Tomorrow morning your name will be manure.
各大媒体 人人得而诛之
You will be roasted alive by the national press.
不容易啊 一夜之间
It falls to few people to be, in the space of 24 hours,
她从圣方济各变成圣女贞德
both St Francis and St Joan.
汉弗莱 千万得想办法 不能关农场
Humphrey, something must be done to stop this farm closing.
不然我们会变成...
Otherwise, we shall look a complete...
喂? 戴斯蒙·格雷布克爵士来了
Yes? Sir Desmond Glazebrook is outside.
格雷布克 他想干嘛?
What does he want?
我还真猜不到     让他进来
I can't imagine. Send him in!
反正今天行政部算门户大开了
It's Open Day at the Department!
大臣 我正好路过 有个主意
Minister, I was passing and I've had an idea.
如果你批准我们加盖9层的话
If you gave us permission for an extra nine storeys...
9层? 不是6层吗
You asked for six!
对 可如果你批9层 我们就推迟三期工程
you gave us nine extra storeys, we could postpone phase three
推迟7年 空着这块地      怎样?
for seven years, leaving this site vacant.
今早我读金融时报
I was reading this morning in the Financial Times
读到您访问城市农场 精彩之至
about your visit to the city farm, a jolly good wheeze.
三期工程那块地就在200码外
Our phase three site is only 200 yards away,
可以拿来扩展农场
so you could use it to extend the farm
就算搬过去 也比原来大
or if they had to move, it's a bit larger.
我们打算命名为
We thought of calling it
"詹姆斯·哈克可爱动物庇护所"
"The James Hacker Cuddly Animal Sanctuary."
反正是"动物庇护所"
Well, "Animal Sanctuary", anyway.
9层不算高吧?
Nine storeys isn't very much, is it?
"詹姆斯·哈克动物庇护所"
"James Hacker Animal Sanctuary."
汉弗莱你看 政府不能贸然
Government has to be awfully careful
扼杀小企业吧?
about throttling small businesses.
银行并不是小企业
The bank isn't actually a small business.
扼杀之后就是了 伯纳
It would be if we throttled it, Bernard.
毕竟 有这么多高楼了 多一幢又怎样?
After all, what is another tower block where there are so many?
是的 大臣 确实如此
Yes, indeed, Minister.
我必须重新考虑我的决定
I shall be forced to reconsider my decision.
我想可以批给戴斯蒙爵士6层楼...
We'll be able to give Sir Desmond his six storeys...
9层
Nine.
给戴斯蒙爵士9层 赶快向媒体发布吧
Nine storeys. Let's make a press announcement.
"詹姆斯·哈克动物庇护所"
To the James Hacker Animal Sanctuary!
您不是担心伦敦公共交通嘛
You were worried about London Transport.
伦敦交通部门会很高兴创收的
They will be glad of the extra fares.
至于小学操场呢
As for the school...
他们没准还喜欢阴凉呢
They might welcome the shade.
尤其在热天
In the hot weather, certainly.
隐私呢?     隐私是相互的 对吧
And privacy? There are two sides to privacy.
人们也许就爱看那些办公楼里的事
People might enjoy looking at what goes on in those offices.
办公楼里总是很神奇的 对吗 汉弗莱?
Extraordinary things go on in offices, don't they?
是 大臣
Yes, Minister.